We've seen that a CNN is composed of several layers.
我们已经知道 CNN 由多个层级组成
We, as deep learning professionals, design the architecture.
作为深度学习专业人士 我们设计了这一架构
This involves setting numerous hyper parameters such as the size of our windows,
包括设置很多个超参数 例如窗口大小
the stride, and the padding.
stride 和填充
After setting our architecture,
设置架构后
we choose a last function and an optimizer.
我们选择损失函数和优化程序
Then, we set the model to train and we wait.
然后设置训练模型并等待
The state of the art CNN architectures that we've
我们讨论的并且在 Keras 中
discussed and that are available in Keras are
有提供的前沿性 CNN 架构
a result of careful experimentation with near
是经过多次仔细实验几乎无限个架构
countless architectures and extensive hyper parameter tuning.
和调试大量超参数后的成果
They are a result of many years of expertise and months of dedicated work.
它们是多年的专业知识和好几个月的努力工作带来的成果
They've been trained on the very large ImageNet database.
它们在庞大的 ImageNet 数据库上进行了训练
And often took weeks to train and that's on state of the art GPUs.
经常需要好几周的训练时间 而且使用的是前沿的 GPU
This begs the question of how to adapt these CNN architectures that have learned
这就引出了一个问题：对于这些已经深入学会如何从图片中寻找规律的 CNN 架构
so much about how to find patterns in image data towards our own classification tasks.
如何调整这些 CNN 以用到我们自己的分类任务中
Instead of constructing a CNN from scratch,
我们如何不用从头构建一个 CNN
how can we take that learned understanding and pass it on to a new deep learning model?
而是运用所学的知识并传递给新的深度学习模型？
This is best accomplished through a technique called transfer learning.
我们可以通过一种叫做迁移学习的技巧顺利实现这一目标
But you may be wondering,
但是你可能会疑问
if you take a CNN that has been trained on the ImageNet database,
如果你用这个在 ImageNet 数据库上经过训练的 CNN
well that CNN has learned to distinguish between
该 CNN 已经学会区分 ImageNet 中存在的
the 1000 different categories that are present in ImageNet.
1000 种不同类别的图片
Most of those categories are animals,
大部分类别都是动物
fruits, and vegetables, or everyday objects.
水果 植物或日常物品
Now, see that the image database that you're interested
现在假设你感兴趣的图片数据库
in has no overlap with those image categories.
与这些图片类别没有重叠
Is it still possible to use that pre-trained CNNs knowledge?
依然能够使用这个提前训练好的 CNN 吗？
Is it even relevant to this new task?
甚至与新的任务有关联吗？
The answer is most definitely yes.
答案是绝对肯定的
In fact, we saw in the previous video that
实际上 我们在上个视频中看到
the convolutional filters in a trained CNN are arranged in a hierarchy.
训练好的 CNN 中的卷积过滤器按层级排列
The filters in the first layer often detect edges or blobs of color.
第一个层级中的过滤器通常用于检测边缘或色块
The second layer might detect circles, stripes, and rectangles.
第二个层级可能会检测圆圈 条纹和长方形
These are still all very general features that are
这些依然是很普通的特征
useful to analyzing any image in any dataset.
可以用来分析任何数据集中的任何图片
The filters in the final convolutional layers are much more specific.
最后的卷积层中的过滤器更加具体化
If there were birds in the training data set,
如果训练数据集中有鸟类
there are filters that can detect birds.
则有可以检测鸟类的过滤器
If there were cars or bicycles,
如果有汽车或自行车
there are filters to detect wheels and so on.
则有可以检测轮子的过滤器 等等
We'll see that it's then useful to remove the final layers of the network that
我们发现 可以删掉网络中最后几个
are very specific to the training data set while keeping the earlier layers.
非常特定于训练数据集的层级 同时保留之前的层级
Then, we can add one or two more and train only the final layers.
然后我们可以添加一两个层级 仅训练最后的层级
This is one technique for transfer learning but your method will depend on
这是一种迁移学习技巧 但是你的方法将取决于
both the size of your dataset and
数据集的大小
the level of similarity it shares with the ImageNet database.
以及与 ImageNet 数据库的相似程度
For instance, the technique we just mentioned will work well
例如 如果你的数据集相对较小并且与 ImageNet 非常相似
if your data set is relatively small and very similar to ImageNet.
那么我们刚刚提到的技巧效果会很好
We should also mention that Sebastian Thrun,
顺便提下 Sebastian Thrun
along with the team at Stanford,
与斯坦福大学团队
recently used transfer learning to develop a CNN to diagnose skin cancer.
最近利用迁移学习开发了一个诊断皮肤癌的 CNN
The CNN classifies lesions as either benign or malignant and
该 CNN 可以将病灶分类为良性或恶性
achieves better performance than dermatologists for diagnosing some forms of skin cancer.
并且在诊断某些类型的皮肤癌方面 取得的效果比皮肤科医生要高
To construct his model,
为了构建他的这一模型
he used a transfer learning approach with
他使用了迁移学习方法
the inception architecture pre-trained on the ImageNet database.
并利用在 ImageNet 数据库上训练好的 Inception 架构
As a first step,
首先
he removed the final densely connected classification layer
他删掉了最后的密集连接分类层
and added a new fully connected layer.
并添加了新的完全连接层
This layer had far fewer categories,
这一层级的类别少了很多
one for each type of disease class that he wanted to detect.
每个都是他想检测的疾病类别
As for all the other layers in the network,
对于该网络中的所有其他层级
their parameters were initialized with their pre-trained values.
参数都使用提前训练的值初始化
Then, during training the parameters were
在训练过程中
further optimized to fit to the database of skin lesions.
对这些参数进一步优化 以便拟合皮肤病灶数据库
In this case, the model truly benefited from
该模型通过利用在 ImageNet 上提前训练好的神经网络
the headstart that it was given from pre-training on ImageNet.
有了很好的开端并受益很多
This approach with fine tuning the parameters in
如果你的数据集非常庞大
a network with a different final classification layer,
并且与 ImageNet 数据库差别很大
works best if your data set is quite large and very different from the ImageNet database.
那么这种具有不同的最后分类层级并且细调网络参数的方法效果最好